# Curriculum Vitae

Name



Rens van Driel
Role
FrontEnd Developer
Place of residence
Dordrecht



#### **Introductie**

I am a passionate Frontend Developer with affinity with UI Design. Frontend Development for me, is the perfect combination between two activities that make me enthusiastic; problem solving and design thinking.

Over the past year, I've developed a strong foundation in React.js, Vue.js, vanilla JavaScript, and CSS. I quickly became familiar with component based development, props, state, life cycles, React Hooks and React Router. In addition, I know my way around Three.js, framer-motion and react-spring. During a project at Sogeti I also gained knowledge on State Management with Redux and version control with GIT. The flexibility of React and the large ecosystem makes React the ideal candidate for my personal development as a developer.

Besides React I also worked with Vue.js. I first came into contact with API calls (Axios) and state management (Vuex) when working with Vue. Vue is also a framework in which I would like to develop myself further.

I am flexible and quickly learn what it takes to achieve the result I have in mind. Within a year, next to my previous job, I taught myself HTML, CSS, Javascript and React to realize the many ideas I had for applications. In the end I was able to turn my hobby into my job at Sogeti.

Besides my work I can often be found in the climbing gym. Sport climbing is the perfect sport for me. It combines strength, balance, and problem solving. This is why climbing has been my go to sport for the past 12 years. If I get the chance I can be found on real rock in and about Europe. Besides that I love playing a tactical board game with friends, can enjoy a good book, like to blow off some steam with rallying on my racing sim or I'm occupied with setting up my NFT project featuring 3D interactive puzzles (projectgetaways.com).

Portfolio: <a href="https://rensvdriel.com">https://rensvdriel.com</a>
Github: <a href="https://github.com/RensGits">https://github.com/RensGits</a>

## **Expertise**

- React.js
- Vue.js
- HTML
- CSS/SASS
- JavaScript
- GIT
- State management (Redux, Vuex)
- Web Design
- Responsive Design
- Firebase

- Adobe (Illustrator, Indesign, Photoshop)
- Figma
- Web 3.0



# **Work experience and Education**

### **Recent Experience**

02/2021 - 07/2022 Eurofins (via Oxford Global

Resources)

01/2021 - 12/2021 Freelance

12/2020 - 01/2021 Eurofins (via Oxford Global

Resources)

04/2018 - 06/2018 Naturalis Biodiversity Centre

#### **Education**

Applied Biology

Role: Laboratory Technician

Employer: Eurofins (via Oxford Global Resources)

Period: February 2021 – July 2022

#### **Description**

I worked at Eurofins as a Technician in the COVID-19 laboratory in Rijswijk during the most hectic period of the Corona pandemic. My main task here was the data analysis of PCR data. In addition to that, I was involved in handling and administrative processing of non-conformities in the laboratory, writing manuals for the use of equipment and training laboratory personnel.

Languages

Dutch

English

My work at Eurofins has taught me the importance of precise work, accurate documentation and how to work under pressure. In addition, it has given me insight into how a large company operates and need for well-functioning software with intuitive interfaces. With data processing at this scale, it showed me that small design errors can have major consequences in terms of efficiency and the increase in human error. For example, there was little to no form validation and the same data had to be entered in multiple applications or Excel sheets. Bugs in the front-end caused dozens of workflow detours and exceptions, for which in turn large flowcharts had to be created to reduce errors in data entry. When mistakes were made, lengthy reports had to be written and people had to be informed urgently. The pressure was high, as was the room for error. I have seen with my own eyes that an intuitive and well-functioning front-end is essential for a large company. This increased my interest in Frontend Development at the time.

#### **Expertise**

Data-analysis, Writing, Leading a team

Role: Web Developer / Graphic Designer

Employer: Freelance

Period: January 2021 - December 2021

#### **Description**

#### Euroloop:

For Euroloop I did a logo redesign and designed various printed matter such as their letterhead, envelopes, certificates and business cards. At the time the client had some conflicting ideas that I had to deal with. For example, they wanted a new fresh design but also found it difficult to let go of certain elements from the previous design, which were pretty dated in my opinion. Here I learned to find the balance between the customer's demand, my own vision, and how to present possible innovative ideas in a way that also makes



the customer enthusiastic. By presenting different designs and clarifying the logic behind the designs, we eventually came to a product that I received a lot of positive feedback on.

#### Markthandel Middelburg:

For Markthandel Middelburg I designed various printed matter, was responsible for their social media management (Facebook & Instagram) and building and maintaining the website (https://markthandelmiddelburg.nl). The owner wanted a working website online with a small budget fast. For this I had to create clear expectations and justify options within the budget. In the end I submitted a number of HTML/CSS templates and adapted them to their liking. At a later time I built two custom components for the website: a vacancy page with expanding vacancies and an Christmas dinner order form with automatic confirmation email and a order list for the owner. I also made the website fully responsive. I mainly learned here that it is important to create clear expectations towards the customer (don't promise more than you can deliver in a short period of time).

#### **Expertise**

Javascript, Responsive Design, Social Media, Web-applications, Webdesign

Role: Laboratorium Assistent

Employer: Eurofins (via Oxford Global Resources)

Period: December 2020 - January 2021

#### **Description**

I started at Eurofins COVID-19 laboratory as a Laboratory Assistant. My tasks here involved DNA extraction and performing PCR reactions. Although this position was intended for a lower level of experience/education, I learned a lot in this short period. It gave me insight into how a high-volume laboratory pipeline works and what bottlenecks there can be between management and the layers below. For example, I have experienced how important it is that employees' needs are listened to and how their work can be made easier. This helped me later when I got a promotion to Technician. For example, I was able to use a lot of this knowledge in writing clear manuals and personalizing training courses to fit peoples learning styles.

#### **Expertise**

Function: Research Assistant

Employer: Naturalis Biodiversity Centre

Period: April 2018 - June 2018

#### **Description**

During my bachelor I did several internships at Naturalis as a researcher. Here I worked with my supervisor on the evolutionary history of two winged insects. After this, I briefly started working as a Research Assistant to complete the studies we conducted at the time. My role was writing parts of scientific publications, analyzing anatomical data and processing data into 3D models with specialized software. To increase the workability of these models, I took the initiative to integrate these 3D models into PDFs. In this way, these models have become insightful for people without a powerful computer and makes it easy to compare such models by having the ability to simply view and be able to rotate them in PDFs. I was able to use my insight into user experience in an industry that normally receives little attention, and that is something I really enjoyed. This ultimately led to the request from Naturalis to write a manual for the implementation of such 3D models into PDFs, which is still used in the 3D lab of Naturalis to this day.

#### **Expertise**

Data-analysis, Data Visualisation, Scientific writing, 3D Printing, 3D Modeling

